Jinzhen Wang

□ jinzhen.wang@brooklyn.cuny.edu

in jinzhen-wang-54b6boa8

𝚱 jw447.github.io **♀** Brooklyn, NY

Bio

My research focuses on enhancing the ecosystem for scientific data management on High-performance Computing (HPC) systems. In particular, I aim to 1) develop reliable data compression algorithms that effectively reduce the volume of scientific data while maintaining the integrity and quality of the information; 2) design data-adaptive progressive retrieval frameworks that intelligently reconstruct scientific data by trading off the computation overhead and accuracy; 3) create efficient data management middlewares that can support diverse scientific applications on HPC.

RESEARCH INTEREST

Data Compression, Scientific Data Management, Machine Learning, Scientific Visualization

WORK EXPERIENCE

Assistant Professor of Computer and Information Science

Sep 2023 —

Brooklyn College of CUNY

Brooklyn, New York, US

Graduate research intern

Sep 2022 — May 2023

Los Alamos National Laboratory

Los Alamos, New Mexico, US

Explore the impact of lossy data compression on various volume rendering techniques as well as color modes. Design a user study on the users' feedback on the image quality.

Summer research intern

May 2022 — Aug 2022

Los Alamos National Laboratory

Los Alamos, New Mexico, US

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

[BC-CUNY] CISC-1050: Intro to Computer Applications

Fall 2023

[NJIT] ECE-394: Digital Systems Laboratory

Spring 2019

[NJIT] ECE-394: Digital Systems Laboratory

Fall 2018

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Electrical Engineering

New Jersey Institute of Technology, NJ, US

Jan 2018 - Aug 2023

M.S. in Electrical Engineering

New Jersey Institute of Technology, NJ, US

Sep 2015 - May 2017

B.S. in Internet of Things (Electrical Engineering)

Shandong University, China

Sep 2011 - May 2015

Publications (C: conference papers; J: journal papers; W: workshop papers)

- [C4] Jinzhen Wang, Xin Liang, Ben Whitney, Jieyang Chen, Qian Gong, Xubin He, Lipeng Wan, Scott Klasky, Norbert Podhorszki, Qing Liu, Improving Progressive Retrieval for HPC Scientific Data using Deep Neural Network, 2023 IEEE 39th International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE), 2023.
- [J7] **Jinzhen Wang**, Qi Chen, Tong Liu, Qing Liu, Xubin He, zPerf: A Statistical Gray-box Approach to

Jinzhen Wang

☑ jinzhen.wang@brooklyn.cuny.edu

in jinzhen-wang-54b6boa8

9 jw447.github.io

♀ Brooklyn, NY

Performance Modeling and Extrapolation for Scientific Lossy Compression, IEEE Transactions on Computers, 2023.

- [W2] **Jinzhen Wang**, Pascal Grosset, Terece L Turton, James Ahrens, Analyzing the Impact of Lossy Data Reduction on Volume Rendering of Cosmology Data, 2022 IEEE/ACM 8th International Workshop on Data Analysis and Reduction for Big Scientific Data (DRBSD-8), 2022.
- [J6] Nan Wang, Tong Liu, **Jinzhen Wang**, Qing Liu, Shakeel Alibhai, Xubin He, Locality-based transfer learning on compression autoencoder for efficient scientific data lossy compression, Journal of Network and Computer Applications, 2022.
- [W1] Xinying Wang, Lipeng Wan, Jieyang Chen, Qian Gong, Ben Whitney, **Jinzhen Wang**, Ana Gainaru, Qing Liu, Norbert Podhorszki, Dongfang Zhao, Feng Yan, Scott Klasky, *Unbalanced Parallel I/O:* An Often-Neglected Side Effect of Lossy Scientific Data Compression, 2021 7th International Workshop on Data Analysis and Reduction for Big Scientific Data (DRBSD-7), 2021.
- [C3] Tong Liu, Shakeel Alibhai, **Jinzhen Wang**, Qing Liu, Xubin He, Reducing the Training Overhead of the HPC Compression Autoencoder via Dataset Proportioning, 2021 IEEE International Conference on Networking, Architecture and Storage (NAS), 2021.
- [J5] Tong Liu, **Jinzhen Wang**, Qing Liu, Shakeel Alibhai, Tao Lu, Xubin He, High-ratio lossy compression: Exploring the autoencoder to compress scientific data, IEEE Transactions on Big Data, 2021.
- [J4] Zhenlu Qin, **Jinzhen Wang**, Qing Liu, Jieyang Chen, Dave Pugmire, Norbert Podhorszki, Scott Klasky, Estimating Lossy Compressibility of Scientific Data Using Deep Neural Networks, IEEE Letters of the Computer Society, 2020.
- [J3] **Jinzhen Wang**, Tong Liu, Qing Liu, Xubin He, Huizhang Luo, Weiming He, Compression ratio modeling and estimation across error bounds for lossy compression, IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems, 2019.
- [C2] Tong Liu, Shakeel Alibhai, **Jinzhen Wang**, Qing Liu, Xubin He, Chentao Wu, *Exploring Transfer Learning to Reduce Training Overhead of HPC Data in Machine Learning*, 2019 IEEE International Conference on Networking, Architecture and Storage (NAS), 2019.
- [C1] Huizhang Luo, Dan Huang, Qing Liu, Zhenbo Qiao, Hong Jiang, Jing Bi, Haitao Yuan, Mengchu Zhou, **Jinzhen Wang**, Zhenlu Qin, *Identifying Latent Reduced Models to Precondition Lossy Compression*, 2019 IEEE International Parallel and Distributed Processing Symposium (IPDPS), 2019.
- [J2] Zhenbo Qiao, Tao Lu, Huizhang Luo, Qing Liu, Scott Klasky, Norbert Podhorszki, **Jinzhen Wang**, SIRIUS: Enabling Progressive Data Exploration for Extreme-Scale Scientific Data, IEEE Transactions on Multi-Scale Computing Systems, 2018.
- [J1] Huizhang Luo, Qing Liu, Zhenbo Qiao, **Jinzhen Wang**, Mengxiao Wang, Hong Jiang, DuoModel: Leveraging Reduced Model for Data Reduction and Re-Computation on HPC Storage, IEEE Letters of the Computer Society, 2018.

Jinzhen Wang

☑ jinzhen.wang@brooklyn.cuny.edu	in jinzhen-wang-54b6b0a8	9 jw447.github.io	♀ Brooklyn, NY
PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES			
Reviewer for:			
SIAM International Conference on Data Mining			2023
IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering			2022
IEEE Internet of Things Journal			2022
IEEE Transactions on Smart Grid			2020